Ms. Liu, morning.
That's too old-fashioned. That won't do.
Ms. Liu.
Have you eaten yet?
That's even more cliché.
Hello.
Ms. Liu.
Boss Li.
Every single day,
I see you exercising early in the morning.
Your body is really strong.
Pity your eyesight isn't great.
You mistook me for Ms. Liu.
We do look a bit alike.
I took you for...
My eyesight really is terrible.
It's okay.
It doesn't matter.
Bad eyesight doesn't matter either.
Later I'll get you...
...some sheep liver to nourish your eyes.
Thanks.
I don't eat sheep liver.
You don't like sheep liver?
That doesn't matter either.
I can switch it to chicken liver for you.
Or else pig liver.
If that doesn't work...
Chicken liver, sheep liver, pig liver all together...
...boiled in a pot, chopped up, and mixed with rice for you.
For you.
Are you feeding a cat?
You...
Fine.
Xiao Cai.
Buy whatever liver you want.
Even if you buy a bamboo pole...
...I'll eat that too, okay?
As long as you leave first.
Don't hold me up.
Practicing boxing.
Why don't you go outside to practice?
Everyone loves to gossip.
I'm leaving.
Boss Li, morning.
Morning.
All that buildup for nothing.
What style of boxing are you practicing?
This is...
...authentic Chinese boxing.
Tai Chi.
I have a Tai Chi Sword.
What a coincidence.
I knew it.
We have a lot in common.
We often do the same things without planning.
Fine, you practice your boxing here.
I'll go practice at the entrance.
Don't.
I mean your suggestion is excellent.
Let's go practice together outside.
Did I suggest that?
I'm practicing sword.
You're practicing boxing.
Mine is Tai Chi Sword.
Yes.
You practice Tai Chi Sword.
I practice Tai Chi.
If we go outside, people will see...
...how well-matched these two are.
No.
I mean the chemistry.
That's not it either.
Anyway, people will look and see...
...a matching pair.
We workers have strength!
The Professor won't get up in the morning!
I'm feeling unwell.
What are you saying?
I asked why you haven't got up yet.
I don't feel well.
I have a fever.
You have a fever?
You're really burning up.
This...
Tell me, what should we do?
When you're old, your immunity is weak.
Once you get a fever,
it might trigger other problems.
What on earth should we do?
Old Fan,
you have to hang in there.
I'll go get a volunteer for you.
Okay. You must hang in there.
Persistence is victory!
Okay.
Victory belongs to you!
Fine.
You really have to hang in there!
Are you going or not?
If you keep fussing, I won't make it.
Darn it!
Hanyū Eiko!
Help!
Old Fan is dying!
It's nothing.
It's no big deal.
No need to worry.
It is simply...
External invasion of pathogenic wind,
internal damp-heat,
exuberant liver fire,
and deficient lung qi.
Do you understand "deficient lung qi"?
I understand.
What do I understand?
Just tell us what the illness is.
Right.
Use medical language
that you can understand.
He just caught a chill.
Is it just a common cold?
A vulgar way to put it.
But I suppose you could say that.
However...
You must not take it lightly.
You must...
take these three medicines I prescribed on time.
Three times a day.
Guaranteed to cure the illness.
Okay.
Alright?
Understood.
Doctor.
Is this a decoction or pills?
Isn't this just cold capsules?
What did you expect?
But this medicine is really effective.
By the way, the patient...
needs someone dedicated to nursing him.
To prevent him from kicking off the covers when sweating.
How about I do it?
But I'm a girl.
Would it be inconvenient?
Let me do it.
I can make do on the sofa for a while.
I can handle this.
I was a doctor when I was in the army.
Often staying up all night.
Working through the night.
Boss Li.
You were a medic back then, right?
Who?
Who was a medic?
I was a vet.
I often nursed sick pigs.
Stop right there.
Lest the patient hears you.
And gets agitated.
Why?
Treating people or pigs is all about saving lives.
As long as it's work...
I never pick and choose.
Even a skinny pig, I...
Okay.
Boss Li.
That's enough.
I think...
I should do it.
No way.
That's not good.
How can we let a great artist...
do this?
What if he...
vomits on the floor or soils the bed?
What would you do then?
Let me do it.
In the army...
I fed pigs.
Feeding him now...
the Professor is about the same.
How can that be the same?
Alright, say no more.
I'll do it.
Ms. Liu.
When I was a vet back then...
it was also mouthful by mouthful...
feeding water to piglets.
But back then...
I did some technical innovation.
I came up with a clever method.
I and the doctor...
Boss Li.
Keep your voice down.
The patient needs quiet.
Needs quiet.
Otherwise...
let's let him rest here quietly first.
Let's go out for a walk, the two of us.
And study Tai Chi and Tai Chi Sword.
Professor Fan
I'm really sorry
Did I wake you up?
Actually, I wasn't asleep
You weren't asleep?
Here
Drink some water
That's enough
That's about enough
Don't drink so much water
Drink too much and you'll wet the bed
He needs to drink plenty of water right now
To bring down the fever
To help him sweat
That drains a lot of fluids from the body
So you have to drink more water
You need to replenish it in time
Sorry, sorry
It's okay, it's okay
Is it that you...
...are uncomfortable sitting like this?
Here
Come on
Hurry, come sit up
Sit up
Sit up and drink
Ms. Liu, don't
Don't do that, Ms. Liu, you...
Don't
What's wrong? Don't what?
Don't drink so much water
Drinking too much water isn't good either
We just changed the water barrel yesterday
And today it's already hitting the bottom
Isn't that for his immune system?
Before the immune system kicks in
The urinary system will collapse first
Yeah
That makes sense
Makes sense, right?
Yes
Listen to me
Just let him sleep here
Let's go outside and study Tai Chi
I won't sleep
I can't sleep
Unless...
Ms. Liu, you tell me a story
When I was sick as a child
My mom would tell me stories
Alright then
No
You even want Ms. Liu to tell you a story?
Keep it down
Telling stories, right?
Telling stories is my strong suit
I'll tell you one
Boss Li
I'll tell you a ghost story. From Liaozhai
No
I want the childhood...
...feeling of a mother
A ghost story?
You...
You look just like the King of Hell
I'm scared looking at you
Who looks like the King of Hell?
That's enough, Boss Li
Right now, the patient...
...whether physically or mentally...
...is at his weakest
Listen
You have to follow his wishes
If we're following my wishes...
Please ask him to leave now
Why should I leave?
Fine
Alright
Okay
Fine, I'll endure it
I'll endure it
I'll just sit right here
And not say a word
Is that okay?
Good
Okay
Then let's...
Professor
Let's tell a story
Tell a story just like Mom
Once upon a time,
there was a mountain.
Right.
There was a mountain.
And on this mountain,
there was also a temple.
Can you stop messing around?
How am I messing around?
Ask Ms. Liu.
Is what I said true or not?
Is there a temple on the mountain?
Yes.
Let me think...
Well...
Once upon a time, there was a mountain.
On the mountain...
Right.
Yes, there was a temple on the mountain.
I know the rest too.
Not only was there a temple on the mountain,
there was also a little demon that ate people.
Eating people wasn't enough,
it wanted to eat a professor too.
Don't... Let me tell you...
That demon specifically eats professors.
Specifically professors named Fan.
It eats them bite by bite, just like this.
Boss Li!
I'm scared, so scared.
Don't be scared, don't be scared.
Boss Li, what are you doing?
Why are you always making trouble here?
I'm just...
Look at you.
You... this...
It just so happens to be lunchtime.
How about this?
You go to the canteen and get some food.
You're hungry?
No.
What would you like to eat?
No...
It doesn't matter for me.
The key is the Professor.
He is physically weak right now.
He must eat on time.
Didn't the imperial physician say so?
It's best to eat something bland.
A liquid diet is best.
Anyway, you figure it out.
Actually, right now...
get my food as well.
Okay?
That works too.
I'll get your food while I'm at it.
Old Fan.
Sleep well here.
Protect the doctor well.
Don't move around.
Whatever you do, don't leave.
Old Sun is off!
Ms. Liu
First, I want to thank you for taking such good care of me.
You're too kind.
It's the least I could do.
A close neighbor is better than a distant relative.
Right?
We should take care of each other.
Besides,
for example, if I got sick,
wouldn't you
also take care of me
the way I did for you?
That's for sure.
Exactly.
I'd definitely be attentive and considerate.
No,
Xiao Liu,
I won't let you say things like that.
You will never get sick.
But don't worry,
even if
you don't get sick,
I'll still be attentive and considerate.
Professor,
Professor, just sit tight.
Well,
us seniors
caring for each other,
looking after each other,
is only right and proper.
Yes.
Especially you.
You're learned and talented,
and highly respected.
You've dedicated your life's work and talent
to the next generation.
I've always admired,
admired you the most,
as an intellectual.
Really?
Ms. Liu,
is that really how you see me?
How come I usually
just didn't realize it?
I was too slow.
Too muddled.
Too careless.
But it's not too late now.
We can start over.
I'm back.
You're back so soon.
Boss Li.
Isn't it a coincidence?
I ran into Zhu Zhu and Xiao Xin on the way.
They were going to get food for Grandma Jin.
So I entrusted them to get the food.
We can't let a small thing like getting food
interfere with taking care of the patient.
It's such a big matter.
Taking care of me isn't a big deal.
You ruined my big plan.
What big plan?
I just wanted to ask,
what did you buy for me to eat?
Cornmeal porridge, shredded pickles,
and half a plate of radish leaves.
Keep it light.
You're feeding a rabbit, aren't you?
Isn't this abusing the patient?
I beg you,
right now, immediately,
go buy me some pig trotters and ribs.
Stewed offal, stir-fried liver.
If they don't have those,
gristly meat, anything will do.
I want to eat meat.
Go quickly, okay?
Where am I supposed to find those things for you?
Besides,
your stomach and spleen are weak right now.
You can't eat those things anyway.
You can't eat rich fish and meat.
Right, Ms. Liu?
Right.
He has to eat something light.
I agree.
Can't eat it.
Absolutely no rich fish and meat.
But I...
However,
eating a moderate amount,
for example, something low in cholesterol
and high in nutritional value,
is still okay.
How about this?
I'll go to the cafeteria myself to take a look.
That's good.
You go ahead.
I'll take care of Old Fan.
No need.
I want Ms. Liu.
No need for that.
Then I'll go with Ms. Liu.
The things are heavy.
Come, I'll help you get the food.
No, but Professor Fan needs someone...
Sitting and chatting
isn't as good as getting up and moving.
Let's go together.
Let's go.
The person taking care of him will be here soon.
I can't be without someone taking care of me.
Is it Zhu Zhu or Xiao Xin? Who is it?
Xiao Cai.
Xiao Cai, why is it you?
I just met some college students at the door,
so I took the food from them.
Boss Li.
Guess what's in my bowl?
I brought you some sheep liver.
There's really sheep liver?
Isn't it a coincidence?
The cafeteria is serving sheep liver today.
Come, open your mouth. It's good for your eyes.
I'm not eating it.
It's good for your eyes.
If you don't eat, you'll go blind.
Hurry up, open your mouth.
What time is it now?
Time for my water and medicine, right?
Medicine, huh?
Here.
I'll feed you.
Who asked you to feed me?
I want Ms. Liu.
Ms. Liu?
She can't come.
How come she...
How do you know she can't come?
Of course I know.
I told her not to come.
How could you?
I'm sick as a dog here.
Come on, Old Fan.
A minor headache and fever.
You've been lying there for days.
I've figured it out.
As long as Ms. Liu doesn't come,
this illness of yours
will be cured instantly.
What do you mean?
What do I mean?
Since we're on the subject,
I'd like to ask you.
Ms. Liu coming to take care of you,
is it out of pure concern for a comrade?
Is it out of pure patriotism?
Is it out of a sincere
belief in saving lives?
In his fifties,
he traveled thousands of miles to China.
Stop.
You...
Are you talking about Ms. Liu?
That's Norman Bethune.
Same thing.
Ms. Liu inherited Comrade Norman Bethune's
fearlessness of hardship, filth, and fatigue,
and the spirit of not fearing stench.
How am I smelly?
That's why she came to care for you.
And as for your behavior,
can you be called a noble person?
A pure person?
Can you be called a person with moral integrity?
Can you be called a person
who is free from vulgar interests?
Simply a wolf's ambition!
A beast in human clothing!
Shut your mouth!
What did I do?
You're dumping all these
shit basins and piss pots,
foot-binding cloths and smelly socks on me.
No, as for what you did,
don't you know yourself?
You intentionally sent me away multiple times.
Didn't you?
To create
opportunities for you and Ms. Liu to be alone.
Didn't you?
To achieve your ulterior motives.
What motives?
Old Li, let me tell you.
If we're talking about
having motives,
it's Ms. Liu who
has motives towards me.
Ridiculous.
That is just too ridiculous.
You're turning it around on her?
You didn't expect that, did you?
I didn't.
During the time I sent you away,
in those bits and pieces of time,
Ms. Liu
has already
expressed
that intention to me.
What intention?
You're making it up.
You can really spin a yarn.
I don't believe it.
Not a single word.
Believe it or not.
You have no choice but to believe.
Ms. Liu said it herself.
That I, Fan,
am learned, talented, and highly respected.
That I dedicated my heart and talent
to the next generation.
In her heart,
I am the one she respects and admires most.
The most lovable person!
The one she likes is me,
Fan himself.
Stop being so gross
That holy, upright, and aloof
Ms. Liu
how could she say such mushy things?
But she just had to go and say them.
In front of a patient.
She opened her heart.
No longer hiding anything.
You're making it up.
You're bragging.
Actually,
getting sick
isn't anything to be happy about.
But it's a blessing in disguise.
I have to thank this illness.
It's good that I caught this cold.
You know, Old Li?
Being fit and never getting sick,
sometimes,
isn't necessarily a good thing.
Come in.
Xiao Cai.
Professor Fan.
Come.
Watching TV?
Have a seat.
Sit here.
What are you holding there?
No...
nothing.
What are you doing?
Playing hide-and-seek with us?
It's nothing.
It's just...
Such beautiful flowers.
They smell quite nice too.
Right?
I know this flower.
You know it?
This flower is called...
Carnation.
Thank you.
What carnation?
Carnations are for mothers.
What are you thanking me for?
No, these flowers...
I'm giving them to Ms. Liu.
For Ms. Liu?
Not for me?
Sorry.
So they aren't for you.
But...
isn't it inappropriate to give Ms. Liu carnations?
This isn't a carnation.
Then what flower is it?
I'm not too sure either.
Where is Ms. Liu?
She'll be back in a moment.
Professor Fan.
Um...
You coming here today...
is there some other meaning behind it?
What other meaning could I have?
I just came to...
express my gratitude to Ms. Liu.
Keep it a secret, okay?
Express gratitude?
Why keep it a secret?
Professor Fan.
Look.
I just said it and Ms. Liu is back.
Hurry up.
What's wrong?
Professor Fan has been waiting for you for ages.
Waiting for me?
He's been dying to give you flowers.
To express gratitude, and keep it secret.
I'm going out.
Don't go out...
Don't...
Um...
Don't, don't stop.
Go take care of any urgent business you have.
And...
no rush to come back.
I know.
Um,
Please sit, Professor Fan.
Ms. Liu.
I've put you to so much trouble these past few days.
I came to thank you.
Here are some flowers for you.
No...
Not you...
Why are you being so polite?
No...
Professor Fan, this...
These flowers...
You bought the wrong ones.
Wrong?
How are they wrong?
These are roses.
It's not appropriate for you to give me these.
If you wanted to give me flowers,
you should have given...
yellow lilies,
or daffodils.
Those are for thanking good friends.
But these flowers...
This...
Have you never studied the language of flowers?
How could I not have studied flowers?
Right.
I haven't studied it.
I just thought these flowers were pretty,
so I just bought them.
I'm sorry, Ms. Liu.
Please don't mind.
No...
Really.
I should thank you.
Because for so many years,
no one has given me such...
such beautiful flowers.
I only...
did such a small thing,
and you gave me such beautiful flowers.
I'm simply...
How about this?
I'll treat you to a meal later.
That would be great.
No.
I'll treat you to a meal.
What would you like to eat?
Order whatever you want.
Xiao Cai!
It's terrible!
Xiao Cai,
why are you back again?
Didn't I tell you,
there's no rush to come back?
I know.
But I have something urgent.
No matter how urgent, it's not as...
This *is* urgent!
I mean, haven't you finished your business yet?
Hurry up and go, go on.
Go handle it.
What do you mean "go"?
Let me finish what I'm saying!
Boss Li, Li Jianguo...
he's sick again.
Oh my heavens.
I'll go take a look.